本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
圣  城  风  云
『第一季  第十集』
翻译  小易
翻译  小熊嘟嘟
翻译  ala365
翻译  苏小黛
时间轴  veryink
后期  渔夫
特效  WiLL
总监制  苏小黛
今晚  你们将为了摩根·彭德拉根而战
Tonight,you fight for the cause of Morgan Pendragon.
夺走她王位的人就在那建筑里
The man who wears her crown stands in that building.
太阳一定会在他破碎焦黑的尸首上升起
The sun must rise on his shredded,burning corpse.
现在  有谁自信可以杀死亚瑟
Now,which one of you believes he can take the sword
夺取宝剑带回给我
from the king's dead hands,and bring it to me?
援军正在路上
More men are on their way,
但凭借夜色的掩护  我们会派出探子
but we have the cover of night,and we'll send an advance scout
刺探那里还剩多少人
to find out how many are left in there.
亚瑟说会在此跟我们会合
Arthur said he would meet us here.
我们暂时驻扎在此吧
We should shelter here for now;
看看伤员的伤势
see to the wounded.
我们在这里等亚瑟
We'll wait here for Arthur.
你很幸运
You were lucky.
不觉得
Don't feel it.
看到他了吗
Any sign of him?
没有
No.
他说过随后就来的
He said he'd be right behind us.
他留下是为了向我们证明自己
He stayed behind to prove himself to us.
向我证明
To me.
我早该料到的
I should have known.
固执的混蛋
Stubborn bastard.
他要对付多少人
How many is he up against?
他去了很久了
It's been too long.
该你了
Your turn.
快点
Hurry.
分散开
Spread out.
我们抓到他了
We've got him!
拿着剑  全速回去
Take the sword. As fast as you can.
我来解决这小子
I'll finish off the boy.
别叫我小子
Don't call me boy.
豪威尔
Harwell!
华莱士呢
Where's Wallace?
在解决国王  他让我将这个带给你
Finishing off the king. He told me to bring you this.
他们包围了孤军奋战的亚瑟
They have Arthur surrounded. He's alone in there.
带上我的问候  直接交给摩根
Take it straight to Morgan,with my compliments.
骑快点  我随后跟上
Ride fast. I'll follow you.
等我一把火烧了国王的尸首就跟上
After I've put a burning torch to the king's body.
国王在哪里  他在吗  我要见我王弟
Where is the king? Is he here? I need to see my brother!
亚瑟王正在巴尔东击退敌军
King Arthur is out at Bardon Pass,repelling an attack.
-伊格兰夫人  -放开国王的母亲
- ...Lady Igraine this way! - Untie the king's mother!
放开他们
Release them!
在你们行动之前  听着
Before you do anything,listen.
国家正处于危难之中
The realm is under threat.
这巫师和国王的母亲闯入了我们的城堡
The sorcerer and the king's mother ransacked our castle,
威胁摩根的生命
threatened Morgan's life!
这些是来自四方的人民
These people have come from all over the realm.
他们遭受了袭击
They've been attacked.
需要国王的保护
They need their king's protection.
我知道卡米洛特的许多男人
I know many of Camelot's men are
正在外围剿叛乱
out in the realm fighting these insurgencies.
我的护卫可以帮助你们
My guards can help you.
你们的眼睛都是雪亮的
You are good men of strong judgment.
作出判断吧
Use it now.
拘押巫师
Restrain the sorcerer,
在我王弟回来之前  给我们保护吧
and give us protection until the king,my brother,returns.
真奇妙  孩子们在哪都能睡着
It's amazing how children can sleep anywhere.
抱歉
Sorry.
因为他们天真无邪
It's innocence.
不知道未来会有何种凶险
They don't know what's to come.
桂妮维尔
Guinevere,
她怎样了
how is she?
刀伤没什么大碍
That's all right for a sword wound,
但箭伤永远不会痊愈
but an arrow wound will never heal.
-拿着  -好的
- Hold this.  - Of course.
准备好了吗
Ready?
给我
Here.
好了
It's done.
关城门
Seal the gates!
我们一定要保卫卡米洛特
We must protect Camelot from any attack.
进去  给自己找庇护和食物
Go inside. Find yourselves shelter and food.
当国王归来  我们会向他请愿
When the king returns,we shall all address him.
谢谢  夫人
Thank you,milady.
护送伊格兰夫人回房
Escort Lady Igraine to her room.
确保她舒适自在  但不得四处走动
Make sure she's comfortable and that she remains there.
我都看见了  你不会得逞的
I see what you are doing,and you shall not prevail.
我稍后去看你  夫人
I'll visit you shortly,my lady.
你可享受我们共度的那晚
Did you enjoy our night together?
你真以为我是她吗
Did you really think I was her?
我还不错吧  因为那晚...
Was I that good? Because you were...
你棒极了
...fascinating.
她知道吗
Does she know?
你告诉她我们的事了吗
Have you told her what we did?
告诉他你如何辗转索欢了吗
How you gave yourself?
你想怎样对付我都行
Do what you want with me...
但不要碰伊格兰
...but leave Igraine alone.
痛不欲生是吧
It burns, doesn't it?
那种爱莫能助的感觉
That sense of impotence.
看着自己倾尽心血的一切被人剥夺
Watching what you've worked for snatched from you.
好好盯着他  他可是无所不能
Keep a watch on him. He's capable of anything.
谁派你来的
Who sent you?!
问这个有什么用
Wha-wha-what does it matter?
当然有用
Oh, it matters.
你为谁效力
Who do you fight for?!
谁派你来的
Who sent you?
谁
Who?
最后一次机会
Last chance.
摩根·彭德拉根
Morgan Pendragon.
你撒谎
You're lying.
袭击巴尔东关口
Attack Bardon Pass.
引出国王
Draw out the king.
趁他率兵抵抗  一举将其歼杀
Kill him when he shows up to defend it.
这是你姐姐的命令
Those were your sister's orders.
你们家可真他妈乱透了
You're a fucked-up family, all right.
旗子还在飘  华莱士没回来
The banner flies, and Wallace hasn't returned.
亚瑟肯定还没死
Arthur must still be alive.
怎么可能  让我带两个人下去
How is that possible?! Let me go down, take 2 men.
不  不  等待援军
No! No, wait for reinforcements.
我人手足够
I have enough men coming
管他什么阵法我都照打不误
to overwhelm whatever tricks he has lined up in there.
你们在卡米洛特是安全的
You will be safe here in Camelot.
把卡米洛特当成你们的避难之地吧
Let Camelot be your refuge.
上帝会庇佑一切
God will provide.
夫人  请问国王在哪里
Milady, where is the king?
为什么他不在这里
Why isn't he here?
你这是明知故问
You know where he is.
他当然是在捍守边疆
Protecting the border of his realm.
有人说
People are saying
他和护卫之妻私奔逃走了
that he has run off with his champion's wife.
不许这样中伤我弟弟
Don't speak about my brother in that way.
没有女人能让他弃国家大任于不顾
No woman would distract him from his duties.
桂妮薇尔肯定在这里
Guinevere must be here.
我们去找到她  向大家澄清一切
Let us find her and prove the truth to you.
任何人不许接近他
No one's to go near him.
他是囚犯  又不是动物
He's a prisoner, not an animal.
你看见伊格兰了吗
Have you seen Igraine?
没有
I don't know.
摩根在走廊安排了守卫
Morgan has her guards all along the corridor.
我哪儿都去不了
I can't go anywhere.
你为什么不挣脱
Why don't you break free?
挣脱又怎样
And do what? Hmm?
做个与人民为敌的疯巫师吗
The mad sorcerer against the people?
他们不会再信任我了
They'll never trust me again.
我们需要亚瑟回来
We need Arthur back.
他不来怎么办
What if he doesn't come?
他会的
He will.
我们要相信他会回来
We have to believe he will.
我说过我不想被人打扰
I said I didn't want to be disturbed.
我想你会想看到这个  孩子
I think you'll want to see this, child.
国王之剑
The king's sword.
这是豪威尔的心意
A gift from Harwell.
事成了
It's done?
是的
It is.
真不幸
It's a tragedy.
-都是按照您的指示  -退下吧
- It's what you ordered. - Leave her--
她要为弟弟默哀片刻
to grieve her brother.
我们的时代到了
This is our time.
这是最后一击
This is our final assault.
找到亚瑟
Find Arthur.
把他给我带来  准备好了吗
You bring him to me. We ready?
-准备好了  -开始进攻
- Aye! Yeah! - Then we attack!
在那边
Over there!
你回来了
You came back.
我曾立誓要保护你
I took an oath.
趴下
Down!
里昂提斯
Leontes!
即便今日将命丧于此
If I'm going down,
我也要尽量多杀几个陪葬的
I'm taking as many of them with me as I can.
说得好
Amen to that.
茁逄?
为卡米洛特
For Camelot.
快跑
Run!
撤
Retreat!
一群浑蛋
Stupid bastards!
亚瑟小心
Arthur!!
不
No!
里昂提斯
Leontes!
答应我  要以战士之礼葬我
Promise me a warrior's funeral.
我对不起你
I'm sorry.
没关系  我将去追随我的上帝了
It's all right. I get to meet my God.
好好待她
Treasure her.
我知道你肯定不愿错过这个
I know you'd hate to miss this.
我们这位因仁爱而受难的普罗米修斯
Our very own Prometheus brought low by his love of men.
此乃国王之剑
This is the king's sword.
我刚刚得知
Just brought to me with news...
国王已逝
...of his death.
我为弟弟之死伤心欲绝
My heart breaks for my brother.
那现在怎么办
What now?
谁来保护我们
Who protects us?
谁来继承王位
Who will take the crown?
这些我无权决定
I cannot decide that.
-应该由你继承  -对
- It should be you. - Yes.
承蒙诸位信任  我不胜感动  但...
Your belief touches me, but I...
你责无旁贷
There is... no one else.
你应担起保护百姓之大任
You owe it to your father and your brother
以告慰你父亲和弟弟在天之灵
not to leave these people unprotected.
她说得对
She's right.
摩根  你对在场的人们
Morgan, you have an obligation
对这片土地上的所有人民
to everyone here,
都有庇佑之责
to everyone in the land.
要想走出这黑暗
Out of this... darkness,
这个王国必须拥立第一位女王
the realm must know its first queen.
正是
Yes.
请回应我们
Answer us, please.
这真是你们的意愿吗
Is it truly your will?
是
Yes.
那么...
Then...
...我接受
...I accept,
秉承我弟弟的遗愿
in my brother's memory,
继续发扬彭德拉根精神
to carry on the Pendragon line.
我特地为你挑了这衣服
I picked that out for you.
刚才那套太不像样了
You were looking a bit dishevelled.
你得穿得漂漂亮亮的
You must look your best.
你永远做不了女王
You will never be queen.
你可以生一个国王
You can give birth to a king,
或嫁一个国王
or you marry one,
但你绝对戴不了王冠
but you won't ever get that crown.
你为何要假冒我
Why did you take my face?
我也问过自己同样的问题
I asked myself that same question.
那并不是我选的
It wasn't my choice,
但我现在知道原因了
but now I understand why.
你是所有这一切的起因
You're the birth of all this.
可怜的孩子
You poor child.
这些年你身上到底发生了什么
What happened to you these years?
你令我父女反目
What happened
这就是发生了什么
is that you turned my father against me.
你没来之前  他爱我毫无保留
Until you came, he loved me without question.
接着你和你的小杂种来了
And then you, and your bastard child.
你永远不会明白
You never understood.
现在无所谓了
It doesn't matter now.
你看起来真美  夫人
You look beautiful, my lady.
你想从我这里得到什么
What do you want from me?
慢慢折磨死你
A slow death.
没关系
It's all right.
这虽然致命
It's fatal.
但到你流血致死还有些时候
But it will take some time for you to bleed out.
伊格兰皇后
Queen Igraine.
现在看看你
Look at you now
我父亲深爱的脸蛋  爱到不惜将我流放
that face my father loved enough to banish me.
他没打算流放你
He didn't banish you!
他本想杀了你
He was going to have you killed
就像杀你母亲一样
like your mother.
我把你送走  是为了保护你的安全
I sent you away to keep you safe!
你在说谎
You're lying!
是我救了你
I saved you!
我不信
I don't believe you.
我怜悯你
I took pity on you!
你永远做不了女王
You will never be queen!
他们回来了  是亚瑟
They're coming. It's Arthur!
准备好了吗
Ready?
是真的吗  我做到了吗
Is this it? Have I done it?
是的  我的孩子
Yes, my child.
万事俱备
This was everything.
我明白
I know.
现在登上你的宝座吧  我的女王
Now take your throne, my queen.
你是否愿意发誓
Will you swear
依据法律  和风俗人情
to rule this realm according to the laws
治理这个国家
and customs of its people,
并宽严相济
and to administer justice
执行审判
with mercy?
我愿意
I will.
你是否愿意维护上帝的律法
Will you uphold too the laws of God
和真正的福音教义
and the true teachings of his gospel?
我愿意
I will.
以此王冠为证  我宣布  摩根
With this crown, I anoint you, Morgan,
成为大不列颠首位女王
First Queen of the Britons.
国王回来了
It's the king!
弟弟
My brother!
你还活着
You live!
我知道你的真面目了  姐姐
I know your true face, sister.
一旦听说我的死讯
One rumour of my death,
你们就拥戴新君主
and you proclaim a new leader!
这对国王可是极大的不敬
A king could get offended.
伊格兰在哪里
Where's Igraine?
-你见过伊格兰吗  -没
-Have you seen Igraine? - No.
但我不愿迁怒于你们
Which is hard,
因为我记得在我的加冕礼上
because I remember standing here at my coronation
看到你们眼中充满希望
and seeing hope in all your eyes.
之后我学到了很多
I've learned so much since then.
也犯过一些错误
And I have made mistakes.
但我现在只为一件事而活
But I live for one thing now.
那就是
Your hope.
传承你们的希望
And how to deliver on it.
我们遭受攻击时  你在哪里
We were attacked! Where were you?
-你跑了  -你在哪里
- You went away. - Where were you?
我在哪里  摩根
Where was I, Morgan?
如果她戴上王冠
If she takes the crown,
我来告诉你们可以得到什么
I'll tell you what you get.
恐惧
Fear!
她把恐惧灌输给每个人
That's what she instils in everyone.
恐惧比希望更强大
Fear is so much stronger than hope.
但永远不会获胜
But it will never win.
我要拿回我的剑和王冠
I'll take my sword and my crown.
没那么容易
It's not that easy.
你民心已失
You've lost the will of the people.
那属于国王
That belongs to the king.
闪开
Out of my way!
告诉他们  她干了什么
Tell them what she did.
摩根密谋反叛国王
Morgan plotted against the king.
昨晚我们攻击了巴尔东关口
We were to attack Bardon Pass last night.
我们接到命令  杀死国王
We were sent with orders: kill the king.
他是个骗子  他为了活命信口雌黄
He's a liar. Talking to save his life!
我的护卫  里昂提斯  死在你的人手里
My champion, Leontes, died at the hands of your men.
别听信谎言
You accept the words of liars
他想离间我们
who'd wish to disrupt our unity!
你为何当面誓言旦旦
Why would you profess your loyalty to me in public,
暗地却加害于我
while sending men to kill me in private?
你该知道背叛的惩罚
You understand the punishment for treason.
你还有什么话可说
Have you anything else to say?
不能怪罪她
It wasn't her!
是我指使的
It was me.
我谋划了一切
I planned it all.
摩根毫不知情
I told Morgan none of this.
她也许能正当地成为女王
She may be queen by rights,
但我们的律法是由劳苦大众创造的
but our laws are made by feeble men.
我对叛国罪供认不讳  任凭你们处置
I confess to my treason. Do whatever you want with me.
摩根对此毫不知情
Morgan knew none of it.
抓住她
Hold her.
你知道叛国罪和谋杀罪
You understand the punishment
将被判死刑
for treason and murder is execution.
一切都只是她一人所为吗
Was this all her own doing?
我永远不会密谋反叛你  我的弟弟
I would never plot against you,my brother.
你手上血债累累了
You have blood on your hands.
伊格兰
Igraine.
你来了
You came.
怎么回事  谁干的
What happened? Who did this?
我快死了
I'm dying,
对吗
aren't I?
不  不
No,no.
我不会让你死的  我不让
I won't let you. I won't let you.
你听到了吗
You hear me?
你在做什么
What are you doing?!
我不让你死  我不让
I won't let you. I won't let you.
我不想再失去任何人了
I will not lose anyone else.
住手
Stop!
不  不
No,no!
我不让你以命换命
Not by killing yourself!
我可以救你
I can save you.
保护
Protect...
亚瑟
...Arthur.
请求你
Please.
对不起
I'm sorry.
并非你的过错
It's not your fault.
我发誓
I swear...
我一定不会辜负你的期望
...I will be everything you ever hoped I'd be.
我会比你期望的更好
I will be better.
我会让你以我为豪
And I will make you proud.
我会为你  为我所有的家人
I will build it all here for you.
振兴这里
For all my family.
永别了
Goodbye...
母亲
...Mother.
这就是我的长眠之地吗
Is this where I am to sleep for eternity?
你还指望什么
What did you expect?
盛大的国葬吗
Pomp and glory?
跪下
Kneel.
怎么
What?
我还以为她会来
I thought that she would come.
跪下
Kneel.
世间无上帝
There is no God.
我知道你杀了我母亲
I know you killed my mother.
你的修女承担了罪责  但她并无动机
Your nun confessed to it,but she had no motive.
她站在处刑人的剑下
She stood before the executioner's sword
从容不迫  就好像她是你的护卫
as if she were your champion.
我对你城堡的保护到此为止
My protection of your castle is at an end.
这个
And this--
这是属于你的国王的
this belongs to your king!
并且  我将剥夺你彭德拉根的姓氏
As does the name Pendragon,which I also strip from you.
你无权再以此姓自称
You no longer have the right to call yourself that.
我也再无王姐了
And I no longer have a sister.
这姓氏是我与生俱来的权力
That name is my birthright.
你在这国家之内再无权力可言了
You have no rights in this kingdom anymore.
你不能剥夺我的姓氏
You will not take my name!
听到了吗
You hear me?!
亚瑟
Arthur!
我是彭德拉根
I am pendragon!
你才是无名小人
You are nothing!
你一直就只是我父亲的野种而已
You will always be nothing but my father's bastard!
我还没跟他告别
I never said goodbye.
我还没机会告诉他  他对我有多重要
I never had the chance to say how much he meant to me.
他生前最后一刻还在想着你
He drew his last breath thinking of you.
有些人我们将永生铭记
Those we hold in our hearts
永不言别
we never say goodbye to.
这一席位属于里昂提斯
This seat belongs to Leontes.
它将一直留空  直到我们找到
It remains empty until a champion as true and
像他一样忠实可敬之人
a man as honourable joins us.
它将永远留空
It'll remain cold for all time.
-同意  -同意
- Hear,hear. - Hear,hear.
为了里昂提斯
For Leontes.
For Leontes!
我从未谢过你
I never thanked you.
经历了这一切  你居然想感谢我
After all this,you want to thank me?
你给了我父母  兄弟
You gave me parents and a brother,
他们比我自己都更爱我
all of whom loved me despite myself.
他们成就了今天的我
I'm more than I could ever have been,
现在不过才刚刚开始
and I'm only just beginning.
亚瑟  我要走了
Arthur... I'm leaving.
你不能走
You can't.
我必须走
I have to.
不  一切因你而起  你必须留下鉴证一切
No. This began with you. You stay and you see it through.
-代价太高昂了  -我们都付出了代价
- It's cost me too much. - It's cost all of us!
-所以我们必须继续  -让我走  亚瑟
- That's why we can't stop!  - Let me go,Arthur.
如果身份互换  你一定不会让我走的
If it was the other way around,you wouldn't let me go.
也许你比我坚强
Maybe you're stronger than me.
也许我以前并没意识到这点
And maybe that's what I didn't know.
你会回来吗
Will you come back?
你...
You...
定能成就大业
...will be great.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我现在该怎么办
What do I do now?
帮帮我
Help me.
要成为女王...
To be queen...
你必须...
...you must give birth...
诞下一位国王
...to a king.
我知道这样不对
I know it's wrong...
但我今晚无法独处
...but I don't think I can be alone tonight.
桂妮维尔
Guinevere...
就今晚而已
Just tonight.
他让我好好待你
He told me to treasure you.
照他的话做
Then do.
《本季终》